Arcadio Díaz Quiñones Papers, circa 1944-2019 (bulk 1970-2012 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1959-2019; 17 boxes (1 partial) 2 items
  - AM 2007-4; AM 2016-95; AM 2017-33; AM 2017-99; 2019-114, 1959-2019; 7 boxes (1 partial)
    - Rosman, Silvia, 1990; 1 box (partial)
    - Rotker, Susana, 1997; 1 box (partial)
    - Roylance, Dale, 1982; 1 box (partial)
    - Rudenstine, Neil, 1984; 1 box (partial)
    - Rudigier, Beate, 1996; 1 box (partial)
    - Ruffinelli, Jorge, 1987-1988; 1 box (partial)
    - Ruiz, Pablo, circa 2002, 2014; 1 box (partial)
    - Ruiz Salvador, Antonio, 1971; 1 box (partial)
    - Rutgers University, circa 1989-1992; 1 box (partial)
    - Rutgers University - Dean McCormick, 1989; 1 box (partial)
    - Sabat-Rivers, Georgina, circa 1986-1988; 1 box (partial)
    - Sabato, Hilda, circa 1991; 1 box (partial)
    - Saddleback College, circa 1994-1995; 1 box (partial)
    - Saer, Juan José, circa 1990-2000; 1 box (partial)
    - Salas, Edelmiro, 1986; 1 box (partial)
    - Salgado, Cesar, 1998; 1 box (partial)
    - Salgado, Orlando (Puerto Rico), 2015; 1 box (partial)
    - Salvá, Iván, 1976; 1 box (partial)
    - Salvatore, Ricardo, 2005; 1 box (partial)
    - Samoilovich, Daniel (Argentina), circa 1998-1999; 1 box (partial)
    - Sanabria, Carlos (Hostos Community College), circa 2012; 1 box (partial)
    - Sanabria, Carlos (Puerto Rican Student Union), circa 1970; 1 box (partial)
    - Sánchez, Luis Rafael, circa 1980s-2014; 1 box (partial)
    - Sánchez Mejías, Rolando (Cuba), 1997; 1 box (partial)
    - Sánchez Ortiz, Elba (Puerto Rico), 1986; 1 box (partial)
    - Sánchez-Vidal, Agustín, 1987; 1 box (partial)
    - Sánchez Vilella, Roberto (Puerto Rico), 1981-1983; 1 box (partial)
    - Sanden, Katherine, 2005; 1 box (partial)
    - Santaliz, Coqui, 1982; 1 box (partial)
    - Santaliz, Pedro (Puerto Rico), 1991; 1 box (partial)
    - Santí, Enrico Mario, 1987; 1 box (partial)
    - Santiago, Myrna, circa 1983-1990; 1 box (partial)
    - Santiago, William Fred (Puerto Rico), 1992; 1 box (partial)
    - Santiago Cummings, José M., 1985; 1 box (partial)
    - Santiago Ibarra, Beatriz, 1984; 1 box (partial)
    - Santillana, Editorial, 2011; 1 box (partial)
    - Saporta, Sol, undated; 1 box (partial)
    - Sarduy, Severo, 1983; 1 box (partial)
    - Sárraga, Raquel, 1990; 1 box (partial)
    - Savaní, Jackie, 1987; 1 box (partial)
    - Savoye, Matilde, 1963; 1 box (partial)
    - Scarano, Francisco, circa 1982-1985, 1992; 1 box (partial)
    - Schaffer, Susan, 2005; 1 box (partial)
    - Scherer, Bernd, 1995; 1 box (partial)
    - Schinasi, Michael, circa 1985-1988; 1 box (partial)
    - Schmidt, Friedhelm (Berlin), 1994; 1 box (partial)
    - Schmitt, John, circa 1984-1994; 1 box (partial)
    - Schmidt-Nowara, Christopher, 1996; 1 box (partial)
    - Schomburg, Dean, 2016; 1 box (partial)
    - Schwartz, Jorge, undated; 1 box (partial)
    - Schwartz, Roberto, circa 1987-1989; 1 box (partial)
    - Schwartz, Stuart, 1989; 1 box (partial)
    - Scott, Rebecca, 1986, 1996; 1 box (partial)
    - Segovia, Tomás, 1989, 2003, 2008; 1 box (partial)
    - Seid, Leslie, 1982; 1 box (partial)
    - Serrano Geyls, Raúl (Puerto Rico), 1973, 1984; 1 box (partial)
    - Shapiro, Daniel, 2003; 1 box (partial)
    - Shapiro, Harold, circa 1987-1997; 1 box (partial)
    - Shipley, George (University of Washington), 1970; 1 box (partial)
    - Silén, Iván, circa 1985; 1 box (partial)
    - Simmons, Ruth, 1989, 1994; 1 box (partial)
    - Skármeta, Antonio, circa 1987-1988; 1 box (partial)
    - Smith College, 1996; 1 box (partial)
    - Sommer, Doris, undated; 1 box (partial)
    - Sommers, Joseph, 1971; 1 box (partial)
    - Sonnenfeld, Albert, undated; 1 box (partial)
    - Sorensen, Diana, 1991, 1998; 1 box (partial)
    - Soto, Julio César, 1995; 1 box (partial)
    - Soto, Pedro Juan, 1983; 1 box (partial)
    - Soto Angurel, Julio, 1995; 1 box (partial)
    - Stanford University, undated; 1 box (partial)
    - Stanton, Anthony (Mexico), 2009; 1 box (partial)
    - State University of N.Y. - StonyBrook, 1983, 1989; 1 box (partial)
    - Stein, Stanley, circa 1989-1995; 1 box (partial)
    - Stephanis, Rebecca, 2009; 1 box (partial)
    - Stranaham, Carol P., circa 1985-1987; 1 box (partial)
    - Suárez, Nicomedes, 1989; 1 box (partial)
    - Suárez Galbán, Eugenio, 1994; 1 box (partial)
    - Subirats, Eduardo, circa 1990s; 1 box (partial)
    - Sullivan, James, 1983; 1 box (partial)
    - Supanc, Patrick, 1992; 1 box (partial)
    - Swarthmore College, 1997; 1 box (partial)
    - Symposium SUNY StonyBrook, 2005; 1 box (partial)
    - Szathmary, Arthur, undated; 1 box (partial)
    - Taliercio, Robert, circa 1989-1991; 1 box (partial)
    - Tineo, Gabriela (Argentina), 1997; 1 box (partial)
    - Taller Puertorriqueño (Philadephia), 1988; 1 box (partial)
    - Tamarin, David and Jo Ann, circa 1969-1973; 1 box (partial)
    - Temple University, 1985-1986; 1 box (partial)
    - Terán, Oscar, circa 1990; 1 box (partial)
    - Teres, Harvey, 1991; 1 box (partial)
    - Tió, Teresa - Puerto Rican Portfolios (Graphic Arts), 1996; 1 box (partial)
    - Tinsman, Heidi, circa 1987-1988; 1 box (partial)
    - Tippenhauer, Yasmina, circa 1998; 1 box (partial)
    - Tirado, Yiyo (Puerto Rico), circa 2016; 1 box (partial)
    - Tomich, Dale, 1998; 1 box (partial)
    - Torre, Juan Carlos, 1991; 1 box (partial)
    - Torres-Saillant, Silvio, circa 1990s-2005; 1 box (partial)
    - Traba, Marta (Argentina), circa 1984; 1 box (partial)
      Includes black-and-white photographic print.
    - Trigo-Tió, Enrique (Puerto Rico), 1993, 2003; 1 box (partial)
    - Torruella Leval, Susana, 1998; 1 box (partial)
    - Tufts University, 2005; 1 box (partial)
    - Ullman, Joan, 1970; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad Autónoma de Santo Domingo, 1985; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Buenos Aires, 1993, 1996; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Cartagena, Colombia, 1995; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad Interamerican de Puerto Rico, 1997; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México, 1992, 2011; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM) - Coloquio, 1981; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Puerto Rico, circa 1967-2014; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Puerto Rico - Bayamón, circa 2014-2015; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Puerto Rico - Cayey, circa 2002-2004; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Puerto Rico - Decanato de Estudios Graduados e Investigación, 1991-1992; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Puerto Rico (Departamento de Historia), circa 1988-1993; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Puerto Rico - Mayagüez, circa 1986, 1996; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Puerto Rico - Solidarity, 2017; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Puerto Rico del Sagrado Corazón (Puerto Rico), circa 2005; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad del Turabo (Puerto Rico), circa 1993-2003; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad del Turabo - Doctorado Honoris Causa, 1998; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad del Turabo - Honoris Causa, 1998; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad Simón Bolívar (Caracas), 1992-1993; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Talca, Chile, 2018; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad Nacional de Colombia - Libre de Berlin, undated; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Valladolid, 1992; 1 box (partial)
    - Universiteit Antwerpen, 2004-2005; 1 box (partial)
    - Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg, circa 1997; 1 box (partial)
    - Universitat Pompeu Fabra - Symposio Internacional, 1998; 1 box (partial)
    - University of CA Berkeley, 1998; 1 box (partial)
    - University College London, circa 1983; 1 box (partial)
    - University of Chicago, circa 2011; 1 box (partial)
    - University of Massachusetts, Amherst, 1994; 1 box (partial)
    - University of Michigan Press, 1995; 1 box (partial)
    - University of Notre Dame, circa 2005-2006, 2011; 1 box (partial)
    - University of North Carolina Charlotte, 2009; 1 box (partial)
    - University of North Carolina Press, circa 2001-2002; 1 box (partial)
    - University of Washington, 1969; 1 box (partial)
    - Urrutia, Mayra Rosario, 1999; 1 box (partial)
    - Val Julián, Carmen, 1994; 1 box (partial)
    - Valdés, Juan Gabriel, 1986; 1 box (partial)
    - Valladolid, Junta de Castilla y León, 1993; 1 box (partial)
    - Van Kirk, Margarita, 1986; 1 box (partial)
    - Vargas, Mercedes (Puerto Rico), 2015; 1 box (partial)
    - Vargas Llosa, Mario, circa 1982-1993; 1 box (partial)
    - Vargas Llosa, Mario - Díaz Quiñones, circa 1982-1993; 1 box (partial)
    - Vargas Llosa, Mario (sobre Puerto Rico), 1971; 1 box (partial)
    - Vásquez, Carmen, 1987; 1 box (partial)
    - Vazquez, Alexandra, 2012; 1 box (partial)
    - Vázquez Arce, Carmen, circa 1988; 1 box (partial)
    - Vazquez, Hugo (Cuba), circa 1959-1994; 1 box (partial)
      Materials include Cuban newspapers, the publication Mella (1960), licenses, and pocket book, "Partido Socialista Popular Carnet" (1959).
    - Vázquez, Lourdes, 2004; 1 box (partial)
    - Vázquez Zapata, Larissa (El nuevo día, Puerto Rico), 2003; 1 box (partial)
    - Velázquez, Sonia, undated; 1 box (partial)
    - Venegas, Carlos (Cuba), circa 1995-2002; 1 box (partial)
    - Vera-León, Antonio, circa 1985-1995; 1 box (partial)
    - Vergés, Pedro (Republica Dominicana), 1994; 1 box (partial)
    - Vicens, Nimia (Puerto Rico), circa 1985; 1 box (partial)
    - Vientós, Provín (Puerto Rico), 1983-1984; 1 box (partial)
    - Vientós-Gastón, Nilita (Puerto Rico), circa 1970-1986; 1 box (partial)
    - Villoro, Juan, circa 2011-2015; 1 box (partial)
    - Vitier, Cinto, circa 1980s; 1 box (partial)
    - Walker, Ignacio, circa 1985-1991; 1 box (partial)
    - Wallart, Kerry, 2001; 1 box (partial)
    - Warren, Kay, 1988; 1 box (partial)
    - Warren, Tanya, 2002; 1 box (partial)
    - Warshaw, Evelyn, 1989; 1 box (partial)
    - Wilhelmy, Manfred, 1989; 1 box (partial)
    - Williams, Raymond L., 1991; 1 box (partial)
    - Wood, Michael, circa 1995-2000; 1 box (partial)
    - Woodrow Wilson Center (Richard Morse), circa 1987; 1 box (partial)
    - Young, Elliot (Princeton), circa 1991-1992; 1 box (partial)
    - Zanetti, Oscar (Cuba), 1996; 1 box (partial)
    - Zanetti, Susana (Argentina), 1991; 1 box (partial)
    - Zavala, Iris (Puerto Rico), 1987; 1 box (partial)
- Series 3: Works of Others, 1944-2006; 7 boxes (1 partial)
  This series consists of manuscripts by various authors sent to Díaz Quiñones for criticism, along with some accompanying printed matter. Most of the individuals represented are major Puerto Rican writers and have a following elsewhere in Latin America. The sub-series within this series are organized by accession, with miscellaneous material located at the end.
  This is arranged into four subseries by acquisition number: AM 84-35, AM 84-35A, AM 84-25A, AM 1998-17, and AM 1998-31, and AM 2005-100.
  - AM 84-35, 1944-1982; 2 boxes
    - Alejandro, Roberto, 1981; 1 folder
      - "Desde Dentro" and "Con algo de distancia," 2 Mss, 1981; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Andreu-Iglesias, César, dates not examined; 1 folder
      - "La mona que le pisaron la cola," Ms, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Arce de Vázquez, Margot, dates not examined; 1 folder
      - [Untitled, on Tomás Blanco], Ms, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Desnoes, Edmundo, 1982; 1 folder
      - "El Caribe: Contra y desde," Ms, 1982; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        [with accompanying letter, undated]
    - Droz, Vanessa, 1974; 1 folder
      - Collection of poems, 18 Mss, 1974; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Echeverría, José, 1974-1975; 1 folder
      - "Afuerino," Ms, 19744, 1 folder (partial) (Folder 6)
      - "La liberación de las necesidades: Indicaciones para determinar la tarea de nuestro tiempo," Ms, 1975; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 6)
    - Ferré, Rosario, 1978; 5 folders
      - "Puerto Rican Literature: A Landscape of the Seventies," Ms, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - "Teoría de lo fantástico" and "El regalo," 2 Mss, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - "Fábulas de la garza desangrada," Ms, 1978; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - [Untitled], Ms, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - [Untitled], Ms, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - González, José Luis, 1974-1980; 5 folders
      - "Historia de vecinos" and [Untitled], Mss, 1974; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - "Conversaciones con Jacinto (novela Jonas)," Ms, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - "El país de cuatro pisos," "El escritor en el exilio", dates not examined; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 14)
        [with accompanying letter, 1980]
      - "Plebeyismo y arte en el Puerto Rico de hoy," Mss, undated; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 14)
      - "Literatura e identidad nacional en Puerto Rico," Ms, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - "La llegada," Ms, 1979-1980; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - González, Lydia Milagros, 1980; 1 folder
      - "De cómo bombas y plenas cuentan la historia de nuestras clases trabajadoras," Ms, undated; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 17)
      - "Corta travesía en el Ancón de Loíza," Ms, 1980; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 17)
    - Hernández, Orlando José, 1976-1980; 1 folder
      - "Desencuentros, libaciones: La obra pictórica de Ernesto Álvarez," Ms, 1976; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 1)
      - printed matter, 1979; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 1)
      - essay on Elizabeth Bishop's "A Lifelong Dream of Time and Silence,", 1980; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 1)
      - translations from Elizabeth Bishop, Wallace Stevens, and Louis Reyes Rivera, dates not examined; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 1)
    - Hernández, Orlando José, 1977-1978; 1 folder
      - John Ashbery's poetry translations, 2 Mss, 1977; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 2)
        [with accompanying letter]
      - essay on "Cuentos mágicos" of José Lezama Lima, 1978; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 2)
    - López Ramírez, Tomás, dates not examined; 1 folder
      - "Ciudad que no tiene fantasmas," Ms, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Marqués, René, 1944-1949; 1 folder
      - "Peregrinación," Ms, 1944; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 4)
      - "Palm Sunday," Ms, 1949; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 4)
    - Morales, Jorge A, 1975; 1 folder
      - "Escribalazos," Ms, 1975; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Ramos Collado, Lilliana, 1972-1978; 1 folder
      - "Avión de papel sobre la Isla de Pascua," Ms, 1972-1978; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 6)
      - "Las flores del mal," Ms, 1976; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 6)
        [translation from Baudelaire]
    - Sáez Burgos, Juan, 1967-1976; 1 folder
      - "La maqueta del viento," Ms [poems], 1976; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 7)
      - "Las piedras de la aurora" and "Nunca en el mismo sitio," Mss [poems], 1967; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 7)
    - Sánchez, Luis Rafael, 1976; 6 folders
      - "El oficio y la memoria," Ms, undated; 5 folders (Folder 8-12)
        [interview of LRS by ADQ]
      - "Macho Camacho's Guaracha," Ms, 1976; 1 folder (Folder 13)
        [translation by Benito A. Gutiérrez-Soto]
  - AM 84-35A, undated; 2 folders
    - Reyes Ayala, Rafael: Poems, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Reyes Rivera, Louis: Poems, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - AM 84-25A, AM 1998-17, and AM 1998-31, 1967-1991; 3 boxes (1 partial)
    - Abreu Adorno, Manuel, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Arce, Margot, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Droz, Vanessa, 1974; 1 box (1 partial)
      - "La búsqueda asesina (poema inconcluso) de Luis Palés Matos," AMs, 1974, 21 pp., 1 box (partial)
      - "La cicatriz a medias," TMs (Xerox), [1970s], 40 pp., dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Ferré, Rosario:], dates not examined; 2 boxes (2 partial)
      - [1], undated; 1 box (partial)
      - [2], undated; 1 box (partial)
    - Fowler [Calzada], Víctor, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - García Marruz, Fina, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Glantz, Margo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - González, José Luis, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Martínez, Jan, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Matos Paoli, Francisco, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Monsiváis, Carlos, 1986; 1 box (1 partial)
      - "Hacia una crónica del nacionalismo popular," AMsS, 1986, 24 pp., 1 box (partial)
    - Morales, Jorge A., dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Ojeda, Félix, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Pabón, Milton, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
      [Strike at the University of Puerto Rico, 1981-1982]
    - Poesía Puertorriqueña, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Proyecto, dates not examined; 1 box (1 partial)
      - Plan Divulgación, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Ramos Collado, Lilliana, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
      [poemario]
    - Ramos Otero, Manuel, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Sáez Burgos, Juan, 1991; 1 box (1 partial)
      - "Poemas portátiles," TMs (Xerox), 1991; 1 box (partial)
    - Sánchez, Luis Rafael, 1967; 1 box (1 partial)
      - "La pasión según Antígona Pérez. Crónica americana en dos actos," printed and bound copy, inscribed to ADQ, 1967; 1 box (partial)
    - Sepúlveda, Arnaldo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Serra Deliz, Wenceslao, dates not examined; 1 box (1 partial)
      - "Memoria" [poems], dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - del Valle, Manuel, and Frank Aswad Sewer, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 box (1 partial)
      - Manuscripts for the weekly journal Avance by various authors, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
  - AM 2005-100, 1993-2004; 1 box
    - Luna, Noel, 1993-2004; 1 box
      - Eros/Ion [poems], 1993-1996; 1 box (partial)
      - Libro de la noche [poems], 1995-1996; 1 box (partial)
      - Música de cámera [poems], 2004; 1 box (partial)
  - AM 2017-33; AM 2017-99; AM 2019-16; AM 2019-114, 1978 April-2006; 1 box (1 partial)
    - Copy of "Desimos désimas" by Joserramón Melendes, undated; 1 box (partial)
    - Alvarez Febles, Nelson (Puerto Rico), 2005 November; 1 box (partial)
      Contiene una carta de Nelon Alvarez Febles y unos versos de un libro en proceso "Antología inevitable".
    - González, José Luis (translation by Balderston), 1978 April; 1 box (partial)
      Contains a copy of "Literature and National Identity in Puerto Rico" by José Luis González, translated by Daniel Bladerston.
    - Pérez-Melendez, José Juan (manuscripts), circa 2002-2006; 1 box (partial)
- Series 4: Subject Files, Memorabilia, and Other Materials, 1952-2018; 4 boxes (2 partial)
  Consists of Díaz Quiñones' subject files, including symposiums, syllabi, essays and interviews, "trabajos," personal documents, and other materials, as well as a few files of memorabilia chiefly containing event fliers and programs. Also included is a poster and program from the University of Puerto Rico in Bayamón, and a copy of a map annotated by Juan José Saer.
  Materials are arranged as received by the repository.
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio, circa 1970s-2009; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Albizu, 1991, 1998; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Articles from El Reportero and Claridad ("La política del olvido")., 1980-1982, 1991; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio (Americo Castro Fellowship), 1984; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio (Articulos Madrid), circa 1984; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Birth certificate (copy), 1968; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Coloquio Universidad de Puerto Rico Mayagüez, 1996; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Curriculum, circa 1980s; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio (El arte de la memoria), 1994; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Emeritus Princeton, 2010 May; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Class notebooks - Jean-Pierre Richard (Madrid), circa 1963-1964; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Class notebooks - Jorge Guillén (Puerto Rico), circa 1962; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Class notebooks - José Luis Aranguen (Madrid), circa 1963-1964; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Essays, circa 1982, 1998; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Essays and interviews, circa 1976-2015; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Homage/Retirement, 2009; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - La Memoria Rota (materiales), circa 1952, 1981; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Notas y materiales (Pedreira, Palés Matos, Albizu), circa 1994; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Princeton University, circa 1977-1978, 2010; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio and Roberto Alejandro, 1985; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio (Universidad Complutense de Madrid), circa 1968; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio (Semana de la lengua), 1996; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Seminario (Puerto Rico), 2004; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Syllabi (Princeton), circa 1980s-2016; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Syllabus (Puerto Rico/Princeton), circa 1991; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Symposium, 2009 May; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Teaching Award, 2010; 1 box (partial)
  - Díaz-Quiñones, Arcadio - Trabajos, circa 1979-2016; 1 box (partial)
  - Avance (Puerto Rico), 1972; 1 box (partial)
  - Bandera Roja (Puerto Rico), 1982; 1 box (partial)
  - Gráfica Mexicana del Siglo XX, 2004; 1 box (partial)
  - Gráfica, circa 1998, 2003; 1 box (partial)
  - Memorabilia, circa 1989-2016; 1 box (partial)
  - Memorabilia - Colloquium on Puerto Rico (Princeton), 2017-2018; 1 box (partial)
  - Memorabilia - Islas & Diásporas del Caribe, 2014; 1 box (partial)
  - Memorabilia - Puerto Rican graphic arts (Princeton), 2018; 1 box (partial)
  - Memorabilia - Puerto Rico, circa 1977-2015; 1 box (partial)
  - Cuba - cartilla de alimentos, circa 1990-1994; 1 box (partial)
  - Poster and program (Universidad de Puerto Rico, Bayamón), 2015 September; 1 box (partial)
    Contains poster and program from the University of Puerto Rico in Bayamón related to a tribute for Arcadio Díaz Quiñones.
  - Map annotated by Juan José Saer, circa 2002; 1 box (partial)
    Copy of a map of Sante Fe that Argentine author Juan José Saer annotated to show the spatial references of some of his works of fiction that he gifted to Diaz Quiñones.
  - Manuscripts, letters, and other documents, dates not examined; 1 box
- 32101037589569 (Box 1)
- 32101037589577 (Box 2)
- 32101037589585 (Box 3)
- 32101037589593 (Box 4)
- 32101037589601 (Box 5)
- 32101037589619 (Box 6)
- 32101037589627 (Box 7)
- 32101037589635 (Box 8)
- 32101037589643 (Box 9)
- 32101037589650 (Box 10)
- 32101080828005 (Box 11)
- 32101080828013 (Box 12)
- 32101037589668 (Box 13)
- 32101037589676 (Box 14)
- 32101037589684 (Box 15)
- 32101037589692 (Box 16)
- 32101037589700 (Box 17)
- 32101080828021 (Box 18)
- 32101038568612 (Box 19)
- 32101103421119 (Box 20)
- 32101103421127 (Box 21)
- 32101103421135 (Box 22)
- 32101103421143 (Box 23)
- 32101103421150 (Box 24)
- 32101103421168 (Box 25)
- 32101103421176 (Box 26)
- 32101103421184 (Box 27)
- 32101103421192 (Box P-000120)